so for programmers the most natural type
of consistency is called sequential
consistency and it says that the result
of any execution should be as if
accesses executed by each processor were
executed in order and accesses among
different processors were arbitrarily
interleaved so we are allowed to let
processors take turns in terms of
accessing or let one access several
times before another one does and so on
so we can do any thing we want to inter
leave the accesses from different
processors but what comes from each of
the processors needs to be exactly in
program order so the simplest
implementation of sequential consistency
is one where we remove the should be as
if so pretty much any execution proceeds
by executing accesses from each
processor in order so a core performs
the next memory access only when all
previous access
are complete so in the code that waits
for a flag to be set and then prints the
data we cannot read the data until the
read of the flag has completed remember
that the problem in previous examples
was that we Branch predict this and
leave and read the data then read the
flag and confirm our prediction now we
can still predict but when we get to
reading the data we have to delay that
until the flag has been red at which
point if we read one here by that time
the rights to the flag and data are
complete and we will read the correct
data here or if we read zero here then
we would correct the misprediction and
go back to waiting here so either way
you cannot print wrong data anymore
under sequential consistency here so
this works pretty well except that it's
really really bad for performance